# Michael Curran

## Developer

Passionate Computer Science student and web developer. Using HTML5 and CSS and JS to build all aspects of web applications. I pride myself on understanding and delivering on client's expectations through excellent communication and rational problem solving. My experience has taught me that even the most daunting tasks a developer can face can be overcome by thorough research, strategic planning and a thoughtful approach.

### **Work Experience**

## Volunteer Developer at Spicy Green Book

October 2020 - Present

Currently working with a team to overhaul an existing web application that assists users in finding and patronizing Black owned businesses.

- Identifying bugs and implementing fixes
- Reducing page load speeds by up to 22% by optimizing images.
- Creating wireframes and graphics that adhere to the client's brand using Figma and Adobe Illustrator.

# Full Stack Developer at Freelance

March 2020 - Present

Currently advising and developing all aspects of client facing applications from web design and graphic design to server-side back end logic.

- Reduced bounce rates by up to 17% by simplifying UI/UX Design.
- Creating inspired and unique graphic designs and logos while adhering to the client's brand using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop
- Produced project deliverables 100% on time with minimal necessary rework

# Kitchen Manager at Back East Bar & Grill

October 2014 - October 2019

Commended for having a great management style and excellent communication skills.

- Trained and hired new staff increasing employee retention significantly
- Proposed an inventory management system to cut down food costs
  5% on average.
- Slashed labor costs by 8% by formulating a new scheduling system

#### **Contact Details**

**Phone**: 386-690-0749

**Email**: Mcurran1722@gmail.com **Location**: Colorado Springs, CO

Github:

https://Github.com/micurran

Codepen:

https://codepen.com/micurran

Portfolio:

https://michaelcurran.vercel.app

#### Skills

HTML & CSS	9 years
Javascript	5 years
SEO	5 years
Bootstrap	3 years
Express.js	3 years
MYSQL & MongoDB	3 years
Node.js	3 years
REST API'S	3 years
React.js	2 years
Next.js	1 year
Angular2+	1 year

### Certifications

CIW Site Development Associate

2019 - Present

### Education

Computer Science Western Governors University 2019 - Present